{"tossups": [{"question": "Laryngeals and the sound represented by this letter of the Latin alphabet were deleted in Szemere\u0301nyi's (seh-meh-\"RAIN\"-yee's) law. This letter represents the sound that has the highest amplitudes at the highest frequencies on a spectrogram. A sound change in Romance languages added a prosthetic \"e\" before word-initial clusters of \"[this letter]-impurum\" plus a stop. P\u00c2\u00b7I\u00c2\u00b7E roots may have a pre x called \"[this letter]-mobile.\" This letter represents the sound that is the only English exception to the Sonority Sequencing Principle, and the only fricative phoneme in most theories of Proto-Indo-European. In Italian, this pre x forms opposites and comes from the Latin \"ex.\" This letter names the abstract syntactic structure that exists a ter movement takes place on D-structure. It represents a voiceless alveolar fricative, whose voiced counterpart is \"z.\" English once used a \"long\" variant of this letter resembling lowercase \"f.\" For 10 points, name this letter used to form most plurals in English.", "answer": "s [accept s-impurum or s-impura or impure s; accept s-mobile; accept S-structure]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>s</u></b> [accept <b><u>s-impurum</u></b> or <b><u>s-impura</u></b> or <b><u>impure s</u></b>; accept <b><u>s-mobile</u></b>; accept <b><u>S-structure</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["s", "s", "s-impurum", "s-impura", "impure s", "s-mobile", "S-structure"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Kazlauskas' rule describes the kinetics when a substance with this property reacts with a lip\u00c2\u00b7ase. Sterically similar compounds such as ammonium bi\u00c2\u00b7tar\u00c2\u00b7trate and ammonium bi\u00c2\u00b7mal\u00c2\u00b7ate form a three-component crystal exhibiting a \"quasi\" form of this property. Crystals with this property are denser than those without this property, according to Wallach's rule. Tha\u00c2\u00b7lid\u00c2\u00b7o\u00c2\u00b7mide becomes teratogenic when it acquires this property in vivo. Mosher's acid is an example of a de\u00c2\u00b7riv\u00c2\u00b7a\u00c2\u00b7tizing agent that can separate a substance with this property into its individual components, in a process known as resolution. Biological samples can have their age estimated by quantifying the extent to which amino acids have acquired this property. Solutions with this property are optically inactive. For 10 points, name this property of a chemical mixture in which both en\u00c2\u00b7anti\u00c2\u00b7o\u00c2\u00b7mers are present in equal amounts.", "answer": "racemic [accept racemization or racemate or the property of being a racemic mixture prompt on achiral]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>racemic</u></b> [accept <b><u>racemization</u></b> or <b><u>racemate</u></b> or the <b><u>property of being a racemic mixture prompt on achiral</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["racemic", "racemic", "racemization", "racemate", "property of being a racemic mixture prompt on achiral"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, a man hits on the protagonist at a concert a ter insisting that she translate the Italian lyrics of a song for him. The protagonist of this novel visits a poor, widowed school friend who now sells needlework through her nurse, since rheumatic fever has made her unable to walk. This novel opens by describing how a character never reads except to look at his own page in the Baronetage of England. In a pivotal scene in this novel, a woman hits her head on the pavement a ter jumping down some stairs at Lyme Regis Cobb. A ter  nancial troubles force her family to rent Kellynch Hall to the Cro ts, the protagonist of this novel goes to Bath with Lady Russell and her vain father Sir Walter. For 10 points, Captain Wentworth eventually marries Anne Elliot in what novel, the last written by Jane Austen?", "answer": "Persuasion", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Persuasion</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Persuasion", "Persuasion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Novella d'Andria took over her father's job in this city, but apparently worked from behind a curtain because of her beauty. Enzo of Sardinia spent over twenty years imprisoned in a cage in one of this city's palaces a ter its forces captured him at the Battle of Fossalta, which also allowed this city to abolish serfdom via the Liber Paradisus. Mondino de Luzzi introduced the practice of public dissections and wrote his Anathomia while in this city. A concordat named for this city superseded the Pragmatic Sanction of Bourges (BORJ) and allowed French kings to appoint bishops. Bulgarus and Martinus were among this city's \"Four Doctors,\" glossators who interpreted the rediscovered Code of Justinian. This city lost a brief con lict that began with soldiers from Modena raiding this city's well, called the War of the Oaken Bucket. The Digest was used at an institution in this city, where the trivium and quadrivium were  rst regularly presented. For 10 points, the  rst medieval university was founded in what Italian city?", "answer": "Bologna (boh-LOHN-yah)", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bologna</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bologna", "Bologna"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "boh-LOHN-yah"}, {"question": "At the climax of a story by this author, the protagonist hides outside while a man looks for a match in the dark, then  lees for a Chinaberry tree a ter he cries out like a \"maddened chimpanzee.\" This author wrote a story in which a man who always throws his pay under the door to his newly-wed wife  nds her in bed with the owner of an ice cream parlor named Otis D. Slemmons, who had impressed her with his fake gold coins. In another of her stories, Sykes takes up with Bertha and tries to scare his wife, the washerwoman Delia Jones, by bringing home a snake, but it bites him instead. This author of \"The Gilded Six-Bits\" and \"Sweat\" also wrote a novel set in Florida in which the protagonist's second husband is the mayor of Eatonville, Jody Starks. For 10 points, name this African-American woman who created Janie Crawford in Their Eyes Were Watching God.", "answer": "Zora Neale Hurston", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Zora Neale <b><u>Hurston</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Zora Neale Hurston", "Hurston"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An advocate of this style wrote that buildings should have no unnecessary features and that ornament should only enrich a building's construction in the two \"great rules\" of design he put forth in the book Contrasts. The term \"streaky bacon style\" was used to deride red brick buildings of this movement, which was advocated by the Camden Society and its journal, The Ecclesiologist (eh-KLEEZ-ee-\"ologist\"). The best-known room of an early building in this style is a picture gallery with crimson walls and a papier-mache fan vault ceiling. A memorial in this style consists of a ornate pavilion over a gold statue of a prince and was designed by the architect of the St. Pancras Hotel, George Gilbert Scott. This movement is exempli ed by Augustus Pugin's work on the Houses of Parliament and by Euge\u0300ne Viollet-le-Duc's (ooh-ZHEN vee-oh-LAY-le-dook's) fanciful restorations. This movement is so named because it was inspired by the style Abbot Suger (soo-zhay) used for the Basilica of St. Denis (sahn-dah-NEE). For 10 points, name this architectural movement, which adapted elements such as  lying buttresses from a namesake medieval architecture style.", "answer": "Gothic Revival [or neo-Gothic; or Victorian Gothic; prompt on Gothic, Christian, or Pointed architecture]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gothic Revival</u></b> [or <b><u>neo-Gothic</u></b>; or <b><u>Victorian Gothic</u></b>; prompt on <u>Gothic, Christian,</u> or <u>Pointed architecture</u>]", "acceptable": ["Gothic Revival", "Gothic Revival", "neo-Gothic", "Victorian Gothic"], "promptable": ["Gothic, Christian,", "Pointed architecture"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While on strike to protest the Edict of Discipline, members of these groups were awoken in the middle of the night by musketeers who gave them the options of returning to work or going into exile. The king harangued the largest of these groups by stating that the \"rights and interests of the nation\" were inseparable from himself in the \"Flagellation\" speech. The disbanding of one of these groups prompted a day of riots named for the roof tiles that protesters threw at soldiers. A member of one of these institutions, Louis La Chalotais (shah-loh-TAY), was accused of sending threatening letters to the king and was arrested with  ve of its other members during the Brittany A fair. These institutions were abolished by a \"triumvirate\" of ministers led by Chancellor Maupeou (moh-POO). These institutions sparked and name the  rst stage of the Fronde, and were typically composed of twelve magistrates from the nobility of the robe. For 10 points, name these courts that o ten resisted royal power in pre-Revolution France.", "answer": "parlements (pahr-lay-mawnt(s)) [accept parliaments]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>parlements)</u></b> [accept <b><u>parliaments</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["parlements)", "parlements)", "parliaments"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "pahr-lay-mawnt(s"}, {"question": "This ceremony once included an \"oath of vengeance,\" in which participants promised to pray for God to \"avenge the blood of the prophets upon this nation.\" This ceremony also once included hand gestures accompanying an oath that graphically described a series of physical punishments called \"the penalty\" that was in licted on those who revealed secrets. This ceremony involves watching a dramatic reenactment of the creation and fall of Adam and Eve. Gestures in this ceremony include knocking at the \"veil\" and a handshake known as the \"patriarchal grip,\" or \"Sure Sign of the Nail.\" A ter taking part in this ceremony, which was  rst administered in the upper room of the Red Brick Store in Nauvoo (NOH-voo), participants wear \"temple garments,\" which are a kind of underwear. For 10 points, name this Mormon ceremony in which participants receive instruction on the plan of salvation leading to the return to the presence of God.", "answer": "temple endowment", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "temple <b><u>endowment</u></b>", "acceptable": ["temple endowment", "endowment"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An activity of this kind originating in a Scottish funeral rite is the basis of John Tavener's A Celtic Requiem. This type of activity titles Gyo\u0308rgy Kurta\u0301g's (YURJ KOOR-tahg's) still-expanding eight-volume set of tiny pieces for piano solo or duet. Witold Lutos\u0142awski (VEE-told loo-toh-SWAHV-skee)  rst used \"aleatoric counterpoint\" in a chamber piece titled for Venetian ones. For his Petite Suite, Bizet orchestrated  ve out of twelve pieces from a suite for piano duet titled for these activities. Nijinsky choreographed a ballet to Debussy's  nal orchestral piece, a \"danced poem\" titled for these activities. Coupled instruments playing  xed intervals apart appear in the second movement of Barto\u0301k's Concerto for Orchestra, described as one of these activities \"of Pairs.\" For 10 points, name this type of activity that titles Debussy's Jeux (zhooz), which depicts examples such as hide-and-seek.", "answer": "games [accept children's games or street games or Venetian games; accept \"Game of Pairs\"; accept Jeux venitiens or Jeux d'enfants or Jeux until \"Jeux\" is read]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>games</u></b> [accept <b><u>children's games</u></b> or <b><u>street games</u></b> or <b><u>Venetian games</u></b>; accept <b><u>Game of Pairs</u></b>; accept <b><u>Jeux venitiens</u></b> or <b><u>Jeux d'enfants</u></b> or <b><u>Jeux</u></b> until \"Jeux\" is read]", "acceptable": ["games", "games", "children's games", "street games", "Venetian games", "Game of Pairs", "Jeux venitiens", "Jeux d'enfants", "Jeux"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A hyper-modi ed nucleo\u00c2\u00b7base involved in RNA polymerase II termination, known as \"base J,\" was  rst identi ed in a member of this genus. A disease caused by a member of this genus can be diagnosed from the presence of cardio\u00c2\u00b7megaly accompanied by apical atrophy. In a dramatic example of RNA editing, mitochondrial mRNAs in this organism are  rst synthesized entirely lacking uracils. DFMO, a suicide inhibitor of ornithine de\u00c2\u00b7carboxyl\u00c2\u00b7ase, is an e fective treatment for a disease caused by members of this genus. These pathogens avoid the host immune system by periodically alternating their surface antigens with variant surface glyco\u00c2\u00b7proteins. A disease caused by a member of this genus begins with the appearance of swollen lymph nodes on the back of the neck, known as Winterbottom's sign. Members of this genus include species brucei (\"bruce\"-ee) and cruzi (\"cruise\"-ee). For 10 points, name this genus whose members cause Chagas disease and African sleeping sickness.", "answer": "Trypanosoma [or trypanosomes]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Trypanosoma</u></b> [or <b><u>trypanosomes</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Trypanosoma", "Trypanosoma", "trypanosomes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man faced unrest from his 125 Russian Jewish employees a ter purchasing machines invented by James Bonsack. This man's company was targeted by Lucy Gaston's campaign against \"co  n nails.\" Masked opponents of this man's company destroyed warehouses in Hopkinsville a ter capturing the town, and were known as the Silent Brigade, or the Night Riders. A power company named for this man had its practice of restricting black employees to working in its \"labor department\" based on IQ tests struck down in a landmark 1971 Supreme Court case. Vigilante farmers opposed this man's company in the Black Patch Wars. A 1911 Supreme Court case split this man's company into four competitors, and he donated much of his fortune to Trinity College, which changed its name to honor his family. For 10 points, name this tobacco magnate, the \"father of the modern cigarette\" and namesake of a university in Durham, North Carolina.", "answer": "James Buchanan Duke", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>James Buchanan Duke</u></b>", "acceptable": ["James Buchanan Duke", "James Buchanan Duke"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the Lambda-CDM model, the accelerating expansion of the universe begins at a scale factor equal to this function of omega-sub-matter over two omega-sub-lambda. The radius of a Stro\u0308mgren sphere is proportional to this function of ionizing photon emission rate over recombination rate. The ratio of the cosmic neutrino background temperature to the CMB temperature is this function of four-elevenths. A white dwarf's ordinary and relativistic polytropic equations of state di fer by a factor of this function of density; therefore, in the limit of low mass, the radius of a white dwarf is inversely proportional to this function of its mass. Applying this operation to both sides of Kepler's third law gives an orbit's semi-major axis in terms of this function of the square of its period. For 10 points, name this operation that, a ter dividing by four-thirds pi, is used to  nd the radius of a sphere of known volume.", "answer": "cube root [or taking (something) to the one-thirds power]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>cube root</u></b> [or <b><u>taking (something) to the one-thirds power</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["cube root", "cube root", "taking (something) to the one-thirds power"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a story from this country, a young man bursts a blood vessel a ter being stripped and tied to a table by a crowd that has gathered to watch the killing of 49 steers. A book from this country decries the historical uses of the color red before describing a general's policy of whipping or executing people who didn't wear the correct red ribbons. A leader of this country was criticized in the short story \"The Slaughter House.\" A book from this country devotes its last chapter to the life of Jose Aldao, a bloodthirsty priest who becomes a brigadier general, a ter describing how its main character is shot by an outlaw while traveling in a carriage with his secretary. That book argues that this country must choose civilization over barbarism, as personi ed by the title \"Tiger of the Plains,\" a villainous caudillo (\"cow\"-DEE-yoh). For 10 points, name this country home to Esteban Echeverri\u0301a (AY-chay-veh-REE-uh) and Domingo Sarmiento, whose book Facundo features its gauchos.", "answer": "Argentina [or the Argentine Republic; or Republica Argentina]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Argentina</u></b> [or the <b><u>Argentine Republic</u></b>; or <b><u>Republica Argentina</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Argentina", "Argentina", "Argentine Republic", "Republica Argentina"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This condition appears as an adjective in the title of a book that rejects the so-called \"domestic analogy\" and suggests the possibility of a \"neo-medievalist\" system of \"overlapping structures.\" A thinker identi ed \"Lockean\" and \"Kantian\" as two of three cultures of this condition. The argument that, despite this condition, a society with \"common rules and institutions\" exists is made in Hedley Bull's best-known book, which informed the theories of the English School. This condition is a \"permissive cause\" of war according to a \"level of analysis\" called the \"third image\" that is advocated in a 1959 book. This condition gives rise to the security dilemma and results in a \"self-help\" system. A 1992 article by Constructivist thinker Alexander Wendt is titled for the claim that this condition is what states make of it. In Man, the State, and War, Kenneth Waltz uses this term to refer to the absence of a higher sovereign in the international system. For 10 points, identify this condition of government-less disorder.", "answer": "anarchy [accept \"Anarchy is What States Make of It\"]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>anarchy</u></b> [accept <b><u>Anarchy is What States Make of It</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["anarchy", "anarchy", "Anarchy is What States Make of It"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These particles experience gravitationally induced quantum interference in the C\u00b7O\u00b7W experiment or when \"bouncing\" f f mirrors at ultracold temperatures. One property of these particles may be empirically determined by measuring the difference in Larmor precession frequency when the applied electric field is either parallel or antiparallel to the applied magnetic field. The physical units \"dollars\" and \"cents\" are defined in terms of another property of these particles that is typically computed using the six factor formula. The Institut Laue-Langevin (LAU-uh LAHN-zheh-vahn) has established an upper limit of three times 10 to the minus 26 e-centimeters for their electric dipole moment. An energy of one mega-electron-volt is the cutoff value for whether these particles are considered \"fast\" or \"slow.\" For 10 points, name these particles made of two down quarks and an up quark that are \"moderated\" in nuclear fission reactors.", "answer": "neutrons", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>neutrons</u></b>", "acceptable": ["neutrons", "neutrons"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of this province's \"ten strange wonders\" is a food with an infamously complex name that requires 58 strokes to write. This home of biang biang noodles contains the Zhoo Mausoleum, for which an emperor commissioned a set of six stone reliefs depicting his favorite warhorses. This province contains the Forest of Stelae (STEE-lee), a collection of artifacts that includes the Nestorian Stele. Its capital has a street named Huimin Jie (hway-min jee-eh), which is named a ter the Muslim Hui\u0301 and located near its namesake Grand Mosque. High levels of mercury can be found in the soil near a tomb in this province, where farmers digging a well inadvertently discovered Qin Shi Huang's (chin shur hwahng's) Terracotta Army. Its capital was named Chang'an when it was the seatof the Han and Tang Dynasties. For 10 points, name this province located in central China that contains Xi'an (shee-ahn).", "answer": "Shaanxi (shan-shee)", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Shaanxi</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Shaanxi", "Shaanxi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "shan-shee"}, {"question": "These concepts title a Philip Fisher intellectual history which discusses their \"abolition of privacy.\" An o t-quoted passage claims that each of these things is \"an original existence... and contains not any representative quality, which renders it a copy of any other existence,\" meaning that it is sensible to prefer \"the destruction of the whole world to the scratching of [one's]  nger.\" Chapter 6 of Leviathan presents a list of these concepts and describes them as \"the interior beginnings of voluntary motions.\" These things are indirect if they arise from a \"double relation of impressions and ideas,\" and direct if they are directly caused by pain or pleasure. These things can be \"calm\" or \"violent,\" and are classi ed as impressions caused by re lection. The second book of A Treatise of Human Nature is titled \"of\" these phenomena, and argues that since these things are responsible for all motivations, \"reason is, and ought only to be the slave of\" these things. For 10 points, name these phenomena, similar to emotions, discussed by David Hume.", "answer": "passions [or The Vehement Passions; prompt on emotions or similar answers]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>passions</u></b> [or <b><u>The Vehement Passions</u></b>; prompt on <u>emotions</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["passions", "passions", "The Vehement Passions"], "promptable": ["emotions", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The sister of this novel's protagonist wears a locket with a portrait of her dead  rst husband, which she later replaces with a capsule of poison. Jewish characters in this novel include the bank director Fischel, whose daughter Gerda joins a group of Christian nationalists, and Rachel, who has an a fair with the African page boy Soliman while working as a maid for Diotima. A character in this novel exclaims \"this murderer is musical!\" a ter seeing a prostitute-murdering rapist named Moosbrugger. This novel is divided into the volumes A Sort of Introduction, Pseudoreality Prevails, and Into the Millennium (the Criminals). Walter's wife Clarisse wants to have a child with this novel's protagonist, a mathematician who is put in charge of the Collateral Campaign to honor Emperor Franz Josef's 70-year reign. For 10 points, name this massive un nished novel about Ulrich, written by Robert Musil.", "answer": "The Man Without Qualities [or Der Mann ohne Eigenschai\u0300ten]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Man Without Qualities</u></b> [or <b><u>Der Mann ohne Eigenschai\u0300ten</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Man Without Qualities", "Man Without Qualities", "Der Mann ohne Eigenschai\u0300ten"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An artist with this given name painted a set of Lucretius-inspired panels depicting animals  leeing from cavemen and forest  res. An artist with this  rst name painted a bent-over man in briefs pulling his undershirt over his head in the background of a painting of John pouring water directly onto a chalk-white Jesus. An artist of this name who allegedly subsisted on a diet of boiled eggs painted two women playing bizarre instruments and a man standing on the back of a tusked sea monster in his Perseus Freeing Andromeda. Four men, including a lance-bearing  gure without legs, sleep in a painting by an artist of this given name that Aldous Huxley called \"the greatest picture in the world.\" That artist with this  rst name worked for the Montefeltro family in Urbino, a fact sometimes used to identify the three  gures conversing in the right foreground of one painting. That artist with this given name painted Christ holding a  lag and kneeling on his tomb in The Resurrection, and Christ tied to a pillar in The Flagellation. For 10 points, give this name of Renaissance artists surnamed di Cosimo and della Francesca.", "answer": "Piero [or Piero della Francesca; or Piero di Cosimo]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Piero</u></b> [or <b><u>Piero della Francesca</u></b>; or <b><u>Piero di Cosimo</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Piero", "Piero", "Piero della Francesca", "Piero di Cosimo"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This country announced the \"Buy British Last\" embargo a ter conducting a \"dawn raid\" on the London Stock Exchange to take over Guthrie, a company that owned 200,000 acres of plantations in this country. A ter a Scots Guards platoon massacred unarmed civilians in this country, the  rst \"winning hearts and minds\" strategy was introduced here by Gerald Templer. In this modern-day country, squatter communities were relocated to barbed wire-ringed New Villages via the Briggs Plan. An a  rmative action policy for this country's indigenous people was implemented by the New Economic Policy a ter race riots on May 13, 1969. This country's Communist party fought the British from 1948 to 1960, a con lict dubbed an \"Emergency\" for insurance purposes. Dr. Mahathir bin Mohamad led this country, the site of racial con lict between the bumiputera (boo-mee-poo-teh-rah) and ethnic Chinese. For 10 points, name this country north of Singapore.", "answer": "Malaysia", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Malaysia</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Malaysia", "Malaysia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These functions can be rescaled using Schmidt semi-normalization. The standard proof of Unso\u0308ld's theorem relies on these functions' namesake addition theorem. Applying the spin raising and lowering operators to these functions gives their \"spin-weighted\" variety, which can be used to  nd multipole solutions of Maxwell's equations in a source-free region. The Slater integral of the product of three of these functions is proportional to the product of two Wigner three-j symbols. The simplest of these functions equals the square root of one over four pi. They are the eigenfunctions of the L-squared and L-sub-z operators. To within a normalization factor, the product of one of these functions and an associated Laguerre polynomial gives the wavefunction of the hydrogen atom. For 10 points, identify these functions denoted Y-sub-l-super-m that solve the angular part of Laplace's equation in their namesake coordinate system.", "answer": "spherical harmonics [accept associated Legendre polynomials or regular solid harmonics or irregular solid harmonics before \"addition\", but do not accept or prompt on any of those answers therea ter; prompt on harmonic functions]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>spherical harmonics</u></b> [accept <b><u>associated Legendre polynomials</u></b> or <b><u>regular solid harmonics</u></b> or <b><u>irregular solid harmonics</u></b> before \"addition\", but do not or <b><u>or prompt on any of those answers therea ter</u></b>; prompt on <u>harmonic functions</u>]", "acceptable": ["spherical harmonics", "spherical harmonics", "associated Legendre polynomials", "regular solid harmonics", "irregular solid harmonics", "or prompt on any of those answers therea ter"], "promptable": ["harmonic functions"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}